{
  "reference_number": "9215",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Do nothing until the big polluters such as China and the USA agree to do their part."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Do not set targets. Man is not warming the world. Do not waste my tax payers money on this scaremongery."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Do not set targets."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Yes, change the target to allow carbon emissions."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Get rid of the idea of targets."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "Yes, incoming Governments should be able to remove the targets"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Remove the targets"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "NZ's contribution to world carbon levels is infinitesimal."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Zero carbon is unattainable. Vegetation absorbs carbon and releases oxygen. Without carbon in the atmosphere vegetation dies,\nand we die."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Man can neither create nor destroy carbon. The amount of carbon on this planet is constant. Volcanoes eject more carbon into the\n\natmosphere than man can even contemplate."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Dismantle the Climate Change Commission. This is a whole industry designed to suck money from the gullible."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Dismantle the CCC."
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Dismantle the CCC"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The Zero Carbon Bill should be revoked. It is unattainable and a waste of money."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Climate change is a function of our solar system, not our carbon emissions. Oil and gas are products of decomposition of vegetation.\n\nThe worlds greatest amount of oil and gas is located in the Middle East - but where is the vegetation that produced it.? It is long gone\n(the bible tells us this area was desert 2000 years ago before man even lit a match.!!) It disappeared because the Earth's climate\nchanged without intervention from man.!!"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Waste of time and money, this just expands bureaucracy and creates \"jobs for the boys.\""
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Climate change is a function of the geometry of our solar system. Our sun is not stationary. It swings 9 planets around, Jupiter and\nSaturn many times bigger than Earth. By Newton's 3rd law there must be a reaction to that force, and that causes the sun into an\n\norbit of it's own. For all the planets to realign from any point in time, (that is for the sun to complete it's orbit) probably takes\nthousands of years. So within this timescale the earth will be closer and further from the sun, creating Iceages and warm periods. We\n\nare currently heading for a warm period. There is nothing we can do."
    }
  ]
}
